GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
We will bust Penguin
one day, I promise you.
Harvey, we
cannot let this slide.
You find someone with
the license, they walk.
Miss Falcone, I need to know
that you are not on
some fool's errand
to rebuild your father's empire.
An example needs to be made.
SOFIA: You may think
you have everything,
but there is one
thing you don't have.
The Falcone name.
Is that your plan to
get close to Penguin?
Gain his confidence? What then?
I used to be smart,
brilliant, and now it's gone.
MAN: Never seen
nothing like him before.
(GROWLS)
(CHOKING) Who are you?
GRUNDY: Solomon Grundy.
You know Grundy?
We're the very best of friends.
With your muscles,
we can make money.
We'd like to put
our hat in the ring.
Go get the doc.
(CROWD YELLING)
(FIGHTER GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
- (BONE CRACKS)
- (GROANS)
Good as new.
Dr. Lee Thompkins. Oh,
my God. (LAUGHING)
Now, what is a girl like you
doing in a place like this?
I heard a rumor you were frozen.
I should have known it
was too good to be true.
Hey, you're not still
mad at me, are you?
Mad at you for what?
Killing Kristin Kringle,
or framing Jim for murder
so he would be in prison when
I lost our child? (CHUCKLES)
I'm over all that.
Let's be friends.
- I'm sensing sarcasm.
- Just as sharp as ever.
Actually it's funny
that you mention that.
Good bye, Ed.
Wait.
Holy hell.
Butch Gilzean?
What have you done to him?
Nothing, believe it or not.
And he goes by Grundy now.
Hey, why don't you
hang over there, big fella?
Making sure that wall
doesn't wander off.
(GRUNTS)
I have no idea what
happened to him.
But he's freakishly strong.
Can't remember
anything about his past life
and he seems to love
me, so big improvement.
But I, on the other hand I'm really
hoping to get back to who I was.
When I was on ice my
head got a little scrambled.
Why should I care?
Okay, I came here with Grundy.
Gonna fight, make some
money to get me smart again.
But you, Dr. Leslie Thompkins,
you can fix me.
You want me to fix you?
Oh, you really are dumb.
Okay, you are here
for some reason.
I don't pretend to
know what that is.
But if you help
me, I will help you.
I know you're not really smart
right now, so try to understand this.
I will never help you.
PENGUIN: I was
raised to be a gentleman.
SOFIA: But you're
also practical.
We were seen at dinner
as we have been
the past three nights.
All of Gotham knows you have
the support of the Falcone family.
And I'm fairly certain no
one's watching us now.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I just like to know
where I stand.
This isn't easy for me.
To have someone I
can trust, a real friend.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
You can trust me.
Let's have lunch
tomorrow. Just us.
Till then.
Have a nice dinner?
How long have you been here?
Long enough.
It's time you tell me
what you're planning.
This again?
Ever since you've
come to Gotham,
all you've done is
make Oswald stronger.
It's time I know your endgame.
And if I refuse?
I'll put you on a train home.
I wanna make you a promise.
In a matter of days, I'll have
Cobblepot in the palm of my hand.
If I fail, I'll stay, I'll
go, whatever you want.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Look, the count's good.
Well, now, go
on, get out of here.
See you next month.
(LOUD CRASHING)
Someone down there?
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CAT MEOWS)
Freaking cats.
Oink, oink.
What the...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON POLICE RADIO)
- (SIREN WAILING)
- Hi. Is he really one of ours?
Seems so. He was in the uniform,
but the killer took his badge.
No one recognizes him?
Well, that part we
have not figured out, yet.
Let me show ya.
Good God.
Freaky, huh?
Let's find out who this guy is.
Here we go.
Dave Metzger. You know him?
Seen him around.
Not to speak ill of the dead,
but he was a grade A bastard.
Did he have
enemies on the force?
No, no cop would do this to
another cop and he was a candyman.
Penguin's bagman.
He was the one delivering
payoffs to cops in the precinct.
I mean, that's the rumor.
Yeah, so someone killed
him to send a message.
Where are you going?
To see Penguin.
Maybe he knows why someone
wants to kill his employee.
Don't go stirring the pot!
WAITRESS: Enjoy your
lunch, Mr. Cobblepot.
I need to talk to you.
If it takes less than
three minutes I'm all ears.
A cop was murdered last night.
Dave Metzger, a
bagman on your payroll?
Oh, you think I might
know something.
Sadly this is the first
I'm hearing his name.
A general does not need
to know every foot soldier.
You don't need to know him.
I think someone is trying
to send you a message.
What sort of message.
The killer placed a severed
pig's head over Metzger's own.
Not a very clear message.
It could have all
sorts of meanings.
Metzger may have been
dirty, but he was still a cop.
Someone killed him
and is using his
death to make a point.
If that is in relation
to you, I need to know.
(CHUCKLES) Jim,
if someone had a problem
with me, I would know about it.
And I would deal with it.
Because you're always
one step ahead, Oswald.
It's why I'm alive.
But I would like to help.
- Mr. Penn.
- Right here, Mr. Cobblepot.
Do we have anything that could
assist Detective Gordon in doing his job?
As a matter of fact, sir,
a few days ago Mr. Wally Clarke,
applied for a burglary permit...
The Pork Barrel.
It's a butcher on 3rd Street.
- They specialize in offering the...
- Thanks for the lead.
Enjoy your lunch, Oswald.
PENGUIN: Don't thank me, Jim.
Thank the licensing
system you hate so much.
Now, be sure to let me know
if I need to get more involved.
Till then, I'm
rooting for you, Jim.
(OPERATIC MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
Have a seat, Wally.
You know how much
trouble you're in? Huh?
You know what
we do to cop killers?
I just told him, I
didn't kill nobody.
Specifically not no cop.
Oh, so you didn't lure
Dave Metzger into that alley,
split open his skull and
stick a pig's head on him?
What? (CHUCKLES) Are you crazy?
That's funny. Because we searched
the dumpster behind your apartment
and guess what we found.
HARVEY: Whoa-ho!
Look at that. Porky
don't have no head.
What do you wanna bet?
That head was on
the dead cop we found.
Screw it. I have enough.
I don't need a confession.
I'm charging you with the
murder of Dave Metzger.
Wait, no! It wasn't me.
- It must have been the Prof.
- Who?
The Professor. That's what I called
him, because he talked all fancy.
He was the one who got
me to rob the butchers.
We need a name, a description.
We did it all over the
phone. The whole deal.
I dropped the heads
under the midtown bridge,
the money was there.
I never met the guy.
Never got no name.
What do you mean
"heads"? As in more than one?
How many did this guy want?
There's four.
To think he could have told me
that he only needed
the heads, but no.
I had to drag them to my
house, chop the heads off...
Just shut up.
Do you know what this means?
Yeah. Means there's
three more victims out there.
How many bagmen did
Penguin have in the GCPD?
Wild guess, I'd say four. The
only one I knew was Metzger.
Yeah, well the people who
got paid by those bagmen,
they'll know who they are.
They're not gonna talk.
We'll make them.
Hey, don't leave me
back here with this thing.
Hey!
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
She's not coming.
- What?
- Sofia.
Your lunch date.
It's not a date.
Whatever. She called,
she's not coming.
Did she say why?
Something came up, I
don't know. I wasn't listening.
It's just gonna go to waste.
I want you to follow her
and find out who she's with.
You think she's two timing you?
She and I are not...
This lunch was her idea. Now,
she cancels all of a sudden.
I want to know why. That's all.
Now, Victor!
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
Today, we have
ourselves a treat.
Our beloved, Hammer, will
take on a new challenger.
Just in from...
- Grundy come from swamp.
- (CROWD LAUGHS)
Rules are simple.
Last man standing wins.
Besides that, anything goes.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Whoo-hoo!
Fight!
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
(ALL CHEERING)
What are you doing? Fight!
Grundy fight now?
Yes, now.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Grundy,
Grundy, Grundy, Grundy, Grundy, Grundy...
Yes, yes!
Yes! Grundy, Ed's best friend.
Looks like I got a new cash cow.
Take good care of him, Doc.
And clean up what's
left of Hammer.
HARVEY: We're not
looking to bust nobody.
We just want the name of the
bagman who delivers Penguin's money.
Don't know what you're talking
about, man. I wish I could help.
- Oh, yeah!
- Hey, hey... Whoa, whoa. Relax.
I know a couple of
other guys we can talk to
who aren't such
a douche nozzles.
Seems like you should be looking
for whoever killed Dave Metzger
instead of shaking
down other cops.
I'm trying to save other cops.
More lives are on the line here.
And all you're using is a cop
getting killed to go
on a fishing expedition.
(SNIFFS) Smells like IA to me.
Come on. Just say you're
not helping. We get it, okay?
Get off me.
HARVEY: We're trying to
stop cops from getting killed.
How can none of
you nitwits see that?
You're asking a cop to
snitch on another cop.
It ain't gonna happen. (SCOFFS)
- Fine. We'll do it your way.
- Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, jeez!
Whoo!
- It's gonna be a hot one today, huh?
- Oh. Yeah. It's gotta be 90 out here.
A lot hotter in there.
Probably a 100.
CULPEPPER: Let
me out, you bastards.
You know what, Jim. I
think we forgot to get lunch.
Think we got time?
I could go out for a burger.
All right, Culpepper.
We're gonna be back
in a couple of hours.
CULPEPPER: Hold it. Let me out!
I'm warning you.
Bullock! Bullock? Bullock!
Okay!
(BANGING ON TRUNK)
(PANTING)
Chris Whitlock.
Makes deliveries for the west
side, but don't say I told you.
Where can we find him?
He's supposed to
be in court all day.
My contact on the south side
said the bagman is Jennie Butler.
- Trying to reach her.
- Good.
I just wanna find this guy Whitlock.
Hope he gives us the last name.
Should be getting
out of court soon.
You ever think you'd
be running around
trying to save cops
on Penguin's payroll?
Bad cops.
They deserve to be prosecuted
and stripped of their badges.
Not butchered.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Call the police!
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
A hundred thousand
people in a square mile
and of course
nobody saw nothing.
Or is willing to admit it.
Butler got off duty last night and
not seen since she clocked out.
Whitlock was due in court
at 9:00, but he never showed.
So, they were both abducted,
taken somewhere, killed,
then brought to pose
in front of this building.
Probably for us to find.
It's a hell of a lot of work.
The killer believes his
message is important.
What? That he's gotta
rid the city of dirty cops?
Specifically the ones
who work for Penguin.
No wonder these
guys look on edge.
Where are we on our fourth
bagman? We need an ID.
I'm working on it.
(SAXOPHONE PLAYING)
GORDON: Good afternoon, sir.
Sir.
Detective James Gordon, GCPD.
You've been playing
here all morning?
On and off, you know.
A guy's gotta take a
break every now and then.
Yeah, sure. Did
you see anything?
Anything out of the usual?
Sorry, uh, Detective.
I ain't seen nothing
since the war.
- Right. All right. Have a good one.
- Yeah.
(CLICKS TONGUE) Oh, man. Really?
Let's try this again.
Did you see anything?
An old van. Filippelli
Plumbing on the side.
Parked up the street a
good part of the morning.
- Guy just sitting in there.
- Guy, what did he look like?
White dude. Didn't see his face.
I took a break, I came
back, the van was gone.
All right. Thanks.
Keep the tip.
(STAPLER CLICKING)
What happened to
you, Butch? Grundy?
Look at your hand.
They grew back. How
is that even possible?
Look at this. It's
not even blood.
It's like swamp water.
Grundy from swamp.
Yeah, I heard. You know, you
don't even have a heartbeat.
But you seem to be doing okay.
You know, Ed is not your friend.
He's just using you.
No. Ed, Grundy friend.
Ed, Grundy best friend.
He just wants you to fight,
so he can make money and
make his brain better again.
Once he doesn't need you
anymore, he's just gonna discard you.
Or kill you, if that's
even possible.
Do you understand?
Ed, Grundy best friend.
NYGMA: That's right.
Best buddies. A team.
Not to mention, your
boss's biggest new attraction.
Smells like we're
sticking around for a while.
Fabulous.
Unless of course,
you're gonna fix the broken
connection in this noodle.
Then we wouldn't have
to stick around. We'd be...
- Gone.
- Yes, thank you.
- That's the word you're looking for?
- Yeah.
Of course, I'd pay you.
(SIGHS) I'm patching up Grundy
as long as Cherry tells me to.
That's it. Keep your money.
CHERRY: How's
my best new fighter?
He's gonna be ready
to go again tonight, Doc?
Yeah, sure.
I gotta step out for
a while. I'll be back.
Just make sure you're here.
We got a deal you know?
Yeah. I know.
(DOOR OPENS)
(PATIENTS COUGHING)
Hi, everyone.
I'm sorry to have kept you
waiting. I'll be right with you. Okay?
Right. You can come on in.
Sit right there.
I'll help you up.
One, two, three!
Let's have a listen.
(CHUCKLES)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
Sofia Falcone,
what are you doing?
HARVEY: Yeah. All right.
That was the Mayor's office.
Press has gotten wind.
Things are gonna heat up fast.
Then we catch him fast.
All the cops who
haven't called in.
Han, Petersen, King,
Nakajima, Massengill.
Yeah, so the precinct's
already looking for them,
but I say we take this list to
Penguin, have him point to a name.
No need. Nakajima is the bagman.
How do you know?
Petersen and Massengill are
both hardcore Bible thumpers.
That leaves three. And
I've heard Nakajima is dirty.
Units are already on the way to
his apartment, same as the others.
I say we retrace his beat,
concentrate our resources.
Hold on.
Doesn't something about
this feel weird to you?
Whoever set the trap for
Metzger, knew where he'd be.
And the killer also knew
Butler and Whitlock's schedules.
Are you saying
it's one of our own?
Someone who's fed
up with the corruption
decided to make a stand.
But to kill them and display
their bodies that way?
I know, brother, but it's something
we at least have to consider.
Which means anything
that we say out there...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
We got a lead on the plumbing
van your blind man saw.
It was spotted near the
abandoned dairy on Commerce.
Should we get the strike force?
No. Gordon and I will cover it.
If we need backup,
I'll give you a call.
And until then,
don't say a word.
And that's an order. You got it?
Let's go. Come on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY
AND WHIMPERING)
Oink, oink.
Little piggy.
(GROWLS)
(CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
Our new champion.
(ALL CHEERING)
(CROWD CHANTING)
ZSASZ: So it turns out Sofia
broke her date with you...
It was not a date!
To have lunch with the mayor.
They went to Angelo's.
She had the lobster
ravioli, he had the tagliatelle.
After they parted ways, Sofia went
to the old Gotham Heritage Hotel.
I don't understand. That
place has been vacant for years.
If I may. A couple of
months ago I'd gotten word
a secret buyer had purchased
the hotel at six percent over asking.
I think it's safe to assume
that buyer was Miss Falcone.
But why?
When she got there
she met with this clown.
MR. PENN: The
zoning commissioner.
She had to have had his approval
for the wall and gate she built.
(LAUGHS)
She's making alliances with
politicians, building a fortress,
all the while she's
pretending to be my friend.
She's been planning a war.
Victor, we'll be having a
chat with Miss Falcone.
Just so we are clear,
is this a chat, chat,
or shove in the
trunk kinda chat?
Get the shovel.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Mmm-mmm!
I think I should rent an apartment
with all this money we're making.
Do you have any
openings in your building?
You know what you should
be doing with your winnings
is finding yourself a
neurologist, which I am not.
It has to be you.
You know me, Lee.
You know what this
coconut is truly capable of.
Which is why my answer is no.
I know about your clinic.
I'm guessing that
Cherry let you keep that
as long as you work these fights.
That's the deal that you have, right?
So?
So, I'm guessing that that
means something to you,
which makes you vulnerable to...
To, um...
- Blackmail and threats?
- Yes. Both of those.
All right. So let's hear it.
- What's your brilliant scheme?
- What?
You said you wanted
to force me to help you.
So, what is your threat?
Hit me.
If you don't help
me, I am going to...
Do something to that clinic.
(LAUGHS)
- Oh, my God. You really aren't smart.
- God!
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(RATS SQUEAKING)
Jim.
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERING)
Nakajima, hang tight, buddy.
We're gonna get you out of here.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Grenade!
Run!
Harvey?
Harvey!
Detective James Gordon.
I hope you don't mind if I say,
I'm tickled pink to meet you.
I would shake your
hand, if it were possible.
I'm a big fan. Big, big fan.
Right. My biggest fan is a pig.
Tell me where Harvey Bullock is.
Oh!
That dirty pig.
Why do you waste
your time with him?
He's holding you back.
Or can you not see that?
Oh!
Never you fret.
He's still alive, for
the time being anyway.
But you, Detective, you
are safe as safe can be.
You a cop?
(LAUGHS) What? What
makes you think that?
The things you knew,
the routes and schedules
of the cops you've killed.
If I were a policeman,
you could, what, reason with me?
Appeal to what we
have in common?
Well, Jim... May I call you Jim?
Jim, that's exactly
what I was going to do.
We have nothing in common.
Oh.
I beg to differ, mon frère.
You and I both see all
too well the corruption,
the filth inside the GCPD.
You and I know that
Gotham cannot survive
unless the cancer is cut out.
We both share the same mission.
Only I do it with a
little bit more flair.
Killing Penguin's bagmen
won't change anything.
It will for them.
It will quite a bit.
But, in the larger
scope, you're right.
Which is why it
doesn't stop there.
Not until I've butchered
every single swine
on Penguin's payroll.
That could be half
the department.
I never said it would be pretty.
Oh, it's the same old story.
No one wants to see how the
sausage is made, but once it is made...
Mmm.
Isn't it delicious?
Bite?
You're delusional. You're
not doing this for Gotham,
you're doing it for your
own demented reasons.
My reasons are as
real as they come, Jim.
I've suffered profound loss
at the hands of the
greedy pigs in power.
Profound!
Then tell me, let me help
make it right, without all this.
HARVEY: Jim!
Oops. Got to go.
HARVEY: Jim, where are you?
Never you fear, Detective.
You and I, we'll meet anon.
Don't you touch him!
- Harvey!
- HARVEY: Jim!
Backup's coming.
Harvey.
You heard Gordon, you freak.
Backup's on the way.
You got one chance to run.
Lies from a liar.
They would have
been here by now.
Besides, we both
know, Captain Bullock,
you deserve this.
(GORDON YELLS)
Harvey.
I do hate to cut and run.
(GROANS)
Oopsie daisy!
Hold on, partner.
(CHOKING)
Hold on, buddy. Hold on.
- You're gonna be all right.
- Jim...
You're gonna be all
right, I promise you.
You're gonna be all right.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Hold on, buddy. Hold on.
Hold on, pal.
(WOMAN COUGHING)
I can't miss any more
work. They'll fire me.
It's okay. I'm gonna put you
on strong antibiotics, okay?
Come on!
(BABY CRYING)
Oswald, I didn't know
you were coming over.
I thought I'd surprise you.
I'm sorry I had to cancel our
lunch yesterday. It was unavoidable.
You have to let me
make it up to you.
How about now?
I was actually on my way out.
Oh.
Where to?
This is going to sound
strange, but I can't tell you.
Not yet. I want it
to be a surprise.
The thing is...
The cat's out of the bag.
- I don't understand.
- I know what you're doing!
The old Heritage Hotel,
the fortress from which
you're going to attack me!
What? No.
Oh! Oh! Oh, so you weren't
pretending to be my friend
while building your power base?
(CHUCKLES) I should have known.
But your father's blood
definitely runs through your veins.
- Luckily, not for long.
- Oswald, you're making a mistake.
I'm your friend.
We'll see, won't we?
Now, let's go see
what you're building.
I can't wait!
Barkeep, another grasshopper.
Those won't help.
- All right. Give me your money.
- What?
The money you made... Well,
that he made. Give it to me.
I don't make any promises,
but I'll see what I can do.
Lee, I just gotta know. Why
did you change your mind?
- Is it my charisma?
- Close.
You asked what I was
doing in a place like this.
I don't want to be here. I don't
want to be anywhere near Gotham.
I left. But I
couldn't stay away.
Because the Tetch virus,
it hit The Narrows harder
than anywhere else.
- So?
It was my fault.
Jim, tried to stop the
virus, and I didn't let him.
I was infected, but nonetheless.
I was there, I don't have a
choice. I have to be here.
Wow.
If you wanted to
blackmail me, by the way,
what you should have done was taken
advantage of Grundy being popular.
Threatened to take him away and
then Cherry, afraid of losing her star,
would have forced
me to help you.
Come by the clinic
tomorrow. We'll get started.
Bye, pretty lady.
Ed's gonna be smart again.
Ed's gonna be smart?
Ed's gonna be very smart.
(CHUCKLES)
It's okay, Charlie.
Oswald...
I want you to
know I forgive you.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
ZSASZ: Uh, boss?
PENGUIN: What is this?
What's happening?
Huh. Kids...
You started an orphanage?
I wanted to surprise you next
week when everything was finished.
WOMAN: Children,
back inside, please.
Oswald, I want you to know I
understand the pressure you face.
Your very survival depends on
seeing everyone as a potential threat.
I watched my father
bear that weight for years.
I don't want you
to end up like him.
Sofia, please forgive me.
How can I
when I've already forgiven you?
- Well, you do owe me one thing.
- Anything.
Lunch.
How do you feel
about mac and cheese?
I love it.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
GORDON: Hi.
Hey.
You gave me quite
the scare back there.
How you feeling?
I've had better days.
- Doc says you're gonna be okay.
- Shows what he knows.
The Pyg?
Son of a bitch.
He could have killed me, but
he cut me just deep enough
to make you choose, go after
him, or save my worthless hide.
That wasn't a choice.
Either way, I owe you.
So pay it back now.
Tell me the truth.
How long have you been
taking money from Penguin?
You knew Metzger was the bagman.
You knew Nakajima was dirty.
The Pyg says all this stuff
about you deserving to be killed.
I don't know why I didn't see it
before, maybe I didn't want to.
I just need to know how long?
Are we talking years?
No, just since this
license crap started.
The commissioner
ordered us to comply.
Then Metzger started showing up
with these envelopes stuffed full of cash.
I didn't do nothing I
wouldn't have done anyway.
You gotta understand, Jim.
The bills I got, the debts I got.
It stops.
Stops now.
REPORTER ON TV: officers of
the GCPD have the city on high alert.
Gotham finds itself
gripped by terror
in the hands of a
ritualistic cop killer,
being called Professor Pyg.
He is still at large
after evading the police.
The GCPD are urging
the people to remain calm
and to report any suspicious
activity to GCPD Central Command.
THE PYG: "Two mother
pigs lived in a pen.
"They each had four piglets
"and that made ten.
"All the piglets loved to play.
"And they rolled and they
rolled in the mud all day.
"At night with their
mothers curled up in a heap,
"they squealed and they squealed
"until they went...
"to sleep.
"And sleep well, for
tomorrow the ax shall fall."
English - SDH